Anthony Castleberry

248-403-6557 - Detroit, MI - AnthonyCastleberry.IT@gmail.com - LinkedIn - https://anthonytechblog.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Cloud Engineer experienced in cloud administration and security, leveraging proficiencies in AWS and Azure cloud architectures, knowledgeable in Python, SQL, Linux, Windows OS's and DevOps methodologies. Demonstrated track record in executing large-scale server system administration, and implementations.

SKILLS AND STRENGTHS

A detailed overview of my skills and projects are located here: https://anthonytechblog.com

Cloud and Infrastructure:

- Certified in AWS and Azure Cloud platforms, proficient in Linux, Windows, Python, SQL, Docker, and Kubernetes.
- Skilled in implementing DevOps and cloud engineering practices, including Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CICD) with Lambda, infrastructure as code (IaC) using Terraform or CloudFormation.
- Experienced in constructing and managing scalable, secure, and highly available development and production environments
- Stay current with DevOps industry best practices and emerging technologies.

Cybersecurity and Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC):

- Conducted mock vulnerability assessments utilizing Splunk and Wazuh SIEMs for threat monitoring.
- Utilize security frameworks and policies to mitigate breaches and maintain a strong security posture.
- Monitor workstation activity with Splunk and Wazuh by analyzing log files.
- Familiarity with governance, risk, and compliance frameworks including NIST Cybersecurity, Risk Management, SP 800-53, ISO 27001, HIPAA, Sarbanes-Oxley, and SOC reporting.

Analytical and Communication Skills:

- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills.
- Effective multitasking with emphasis on project and time management.
- Excellent written and verbal communication.
- Proficient in documentation using Excel, Word, and PowerPoint.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Education

- Bachelor of Science (BS) in Information Technology Capella University
- Information Technology Fundamentals Global Information Technology

Certifications

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate AWS
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner AWS
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals Microsoft
- A+ CompTIA
- Network + CompTIA
- Security + CompTIA

EXPERIENCE

Tungsten Automation

Business Development Manager - May 2022 - February 2024

 Create and finalize Professional Service estimates and quotes within Salesforce & develop and maintain detailed product and services documentation

Professional Services Consultant - January 2012 - May 2022

- Drive deployment activities: system evaluations, functional design, user acceptance testing, issue resolution, installation, and training
- Perform technical configuration for software deployments, and collaborate with the project teams for implementation
- Serve as the subject matter expert for client consulting

General Motors - OnStar Advanced Systems Development (ASD)

Desktop support - October 2010 - December 2011

- Monitor data systems, servers, and mobile applications, utilizing E-tracker ticketing and Nagios monitoring systems.
- Perform desk-side support, system restores, desktop re-configurations, part replacements, and Operating System installations.
- Administer Active Directory, including creating, unlocking, and resetting personnel accounts, managing groups, and setting group permissions.

Detroit Public Schools Systems

Ground Support Technician - August 2009 - October 2010

- On-site endpoint support for workstation upgrades, provide desktop support for facility and staff.
- Conduct school-wide workstation inventory, implemented asset tagging, and workstation re-imaging and patching.

ADDITIONAL TRAININGS & EXPERIENCE

TRAININGS

- Security Operations Center (SOC) Level 1 Try Hack Me
- Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate Google
- GRC Analyst Masterclass Simply Cyber

HOME LAB TESTING SETUP

- Virtual Servers Window Server, Splunk SIEM, Wire Shark
- RasberryPi Ubuntu Server Wizuh Test SIEM, Portainer
- Zima board ProxMox, Synology File Server Rust Desk